A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, 1903-1947
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, 1903-1947
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 25/1
84.84 Cubic Feet; 117 boxes
The Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station (VAES) was established in 1886 by an act of the Virginia General Assembly and funded by the federal Hatch Act of 1887 for the purpose of providing practical and useful information on agricultural and scientific subjects. The collection includes 114 surveys books for ten counties in Virginia from 1931 through 1940, as well as files dated 1903-1947 of weather reports, annual reports of investigations of the field laboratories, and a large amount of documentation of various research projects related to crops, orchards, animals, and more. There is also the correspondence of A. W. Drinkard, Jr., director of VAES, with state entomologist and plant pathologist W. J. Schoene, professors at VPI, agricultural organizations, and others.
Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station
Drinkard, Alfred Washington, Jr.
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
Series I of the Records of the Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station was transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in 1955. Series II was transferred in February 1982 and December 1984.
Appraisal
Duplicate copies of the Quarterly Bulletin of the Virginia State Crop Pest Commission were weeded from the collection.
Administrative History
The Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station (VAES) was established in 1886 by an act of the Virginia General Assembly and funded by the federal Hatch Act of 1887 for the purpose of providing practical and useful information on agricultural and scientific subjects. Originally, it was organized into three departments: agriculture, botany and entomology, and chemistry. VAES was responsible for several agricultural research stations and laboratories throughout Virginia. On July 1, 1966, the research activities of the Agricultural Experiment Station, as well as the Engineering Experiment Station, were combined under a University-wide Research Division. In 1978, the VAES moved from the Research Division to the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences (CALS).
Scope and Content
This collection contains primarily farm surveys and reports, which comprise Series I. Survey books. Subjects covered include cattle, crop rotations, insecticides, orchards, etc. There are also statistical surveys on farm operations and productions in ten Virginia counties: Albemarle (1935, 2 vols.); Appomatox (1935-36, 4 vols.); Floyd (1937, 2 vols.); Grayson (1930-31, 8 vols.); Halifax (1939, 7 vols.); Henry (1940, 7 vols.); Nansemond (1932, 17 vols.); Norfolk (1931-32, 7 vols.); Pittsylvania (1933-36, 42 vols.); and Russell (1935, 9 vols.). Also included are 9 volumes of poultry surveys for several Virginia counties (1931-32) and a Truck survey done in 1938.
The second series comprises files dated 1903-1947. Materials include weather reports, annual reports of investigations of the field laboratories, and a large amount of documentation of various research projects related to crops, orchards, animals, and more at different Agricultural Research and Extension Centers (ARECs) across the state. Some of these records are from the earliest established ARECs at Chatham and Appomattox. The series also includes the correspondence of A. W. Drinkard, Jr., director of VAES from 1916 through 1946, with state entomologist and plant pathologist W. J. Schoene, professors and administrators at VPI, agricultural organizations, and others.
Arrangement
The Records of the Virgnina Agricultural Experiment Station are organized by type of material:
Series I. Survey books, 1931-1940, which are organized by county and survey type:
Subseries I. Albemarle County, 1935
Subseries II. Appomattox County, 1935-1936
Subseries III. Floyd County, 1937
Subseries IV. Grayson County, 1937
Subseries V. Halifax County, 1939
Subseries VI. Henry County Land Utilization Study, 1940
Subseries VII. Nansemond County, 1932
Subseries VIII. Norfolk Dairy Survey, 1931-1932
Subseries IX. Pittsylvania County, 1933
Subseries X. Russell County, 1935
Subseries XI. Truck Survey, 1938
Subseries XII. Poultry Survey, 1931-1932
Series II. Files, 1903-1947, which are organized in loose chronological and subject order. Correspondence files are subdivided alphabetically.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Agriculture; Faculty; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Science and Technology; University Archives; University History
Organizations:
Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute (1896-1944); Virginia Engineering Experiment Station; Virginia Polytechnic Institute (1944-1970); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Research Division; Virginia Truck Experiment Station (1907-1967)
People:
Drinkard, Alfred Washington, Jr.
Contents List
- Series I. Survey books, 1931-1940
  - Subseries I. Albemarle County, 1935
    - Albemarle County Record of Farm Business (Vol. I-II), 1935 (Box 1)
  - Subseries II. Appomattox County, 1935-1936
    - Appomattox County Record of Farm Business (Vol. I-II), 1935 (Box 2)
    - Appomattox County Record of Farm Business (Vol. I-II), 1936 (Box 3)
  - Subseries III. Floyd County, 1937
    - Floyd County Tabulations, 1937 (Box 4)
    - Floyd County Records, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Subseries IV. Grayson County, 1931
    - Office Sheets (Vol. I-II), 1931 (Box 7)
    - Land Tenure and Crops (Vol. III), 1931 (Box 6)
    - Livestock Inventory, Livestock Summary, and Livestock Breeding (Vol. IV), 1931 (Box 4)
    - Livestock Products and Receipts from Other Sources (Vol. V), 1931 (Box 9)
    - Feed and Supplies Inventory and Current Expense (Vol. VI), 1931 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Vol. VII), 1931 (Box 8)
    - Worksheet for Tables Used, Tables and Worksheets Not Used (Vol. VIII), 1931 (Box 6)
  - Subseries V. Halifax County, 1939
    - Tabulations (Vol. I-III), 1939 (Box 9, Box 10)
    - Instructions and Code Outlines, 1939 (Box 10)
    - Halifax County Record of Farm Business, 1939 (Box 11, Box 12)
    - Land Classification, 1939 (Box 13)
  - Subseries VI. Henry County Land Utilization Study, 1940
    - Instructions and Card Outlines, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Abandoned Farms, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Farm Record Tabulations, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Mortgage-Tax Data, 1940 (Box 15)
    - Code Sheets, 1940 (Box 18)
    - Land Class (Vol. II-IV), 1940 (Box 16, Box 17)
  - Subseries VII. Nansemond County, 1932
    - Index Volume (Vol. I), 1932 (Box 23)
    - Crops (Vol. II), 1932 (Box 15)
    - Livestock (Vol. III), 1932 (Box 18)
    - Seeds and Feeds and Supplies (Vol. IV), 1932 (Box 20)
    - Fertilizer, Lime, and Manure (Vol. V), 1932 (Box 20)
    - Farm Expenses and Equipment (Vol. VI), 1932 (Box 19)
    - Livestock Products Sold, Receipts, Products used in House, Capital Profits, Miscellaneous (Vol. VII), 1932 (Box 21)
    - Tabulations From Cards and Crops and Livestock (Vol. VIII), 1932 (Box 22)
    - Tabulations from Cards and Effect of Business Factors for the Farm as a Whole Upon Income (Vol. IX), 1932 (Box 22)
    - Cypress White and Except Owners (Vol. X), 1932 (Box 24)
    - Whaleyville White Owners (Vol. XI), 1932 (Box 25)
    - Holyneck White Owners (Vol. XII), 1932 (Box 26)
    - Whaleyville-Holyneck White Except Owners (Vol. XIII), 1932 (Box 27)
    - Cypress-Whaleyville Colored (Vol. XIV), 1932 (Box 27)
    - Holyneck-Colored (Vol. XV), 1932 (Box 28)
    - Nansemond Specials-Owners (Vol. XVI), 1932 (Box 28)
    - Nansemond Specials Except Owners (Incomplete or Inaccurate) Vol. XVII, 1932 (Box 27)
  - Subseries VIII. Norfolk Dairy Survey, 1931-1932
    - Index Volume (Vol. I), 1932 (Box 29)
    - Tabulations for Farm Management (Vol. II-III), 1931 (Box 29, Box 30)
    - Coast Dairy Enterprize (Vol. IV), 1931 (Box 31)
    - Tables for Charts and Worksheets for Tables (Vol. V), 1931 (Box 32)
    - Farm Management Office Sheets (Vol. IV), 1931 (Box 33)
    - Dairy Office Sheets (Vol. VII), 1931 (Box 33)
  - Subseries IX. Pittsylvania County, 1933, 1936
    - Index (Vol. I), 1933 (Box 23)
    - Labor and Tabacco (Vol. I-II), 1933 (Box 34, Box 35)
    - Farm Records (Vol. I-X), 1933 (Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
    - Tobacco Sales, 1933 (Box 34)
    - Machinery and Equipment (Vol. I-III), 1933 (Box 40, Box 41, Box 42)
    - Livestock, 1933 (Box 43)
    - Card Tabulations (Vol. I-III), 1933 (Box 44, Box 45)
    - Operators, Landlords, and Cropper's Businesses, 1933 (Box 45)
    - Fertilizer, Lime, Manure, and Cover Crops, 1933 (Box 46)
    - Seeds, Feeds, and Supplies, 1933 (Box 47)
    - Real Estate Summary, 1933 (Box 47)
    - Products Used in House, List Products Sold, and Misc. Receipts, 1933 (Box 48)
    - Labor Distribution and Cost of Plants, 1933 (Box 48)
    - Selected Croup Cost Summaries, 1933 (Box 49)
    - Farm Expenses Autos Trucks Tractors, 1933 (Box 49)
    - Crops, 1933 (Box 50)
    - Index (Vol. I), 1936 (Box 23)
    - Crops and Fertilizer (Vol. II), 1936 (Box 51)
    - Seed Lime and Manure, Livestock, and Livestock Products (Vol. III), 1936 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous Receipts, Farm Products Furnished, Machinery, and Farm Expense (Vol. IV), 1936 (Box 54)
    - Auto Truck Tractor, Feed and Supply Inventory, Capital, and Summary (Vol. V), 1936 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous (Vol. VI), 1936 (Box 53)
    - Number-Name, Color-Acres, Code Cards, and Tabulations from Cards (Vol. VII), 1936 (Box 55)
    - Owner-Operators without Croppers, 288 and Up (Vol. IX), 1936 (Box 55)
    - Owner-Operators without Croppers, Less than 287 (Vol. X), 1936 (Box 57)
    - Owner Operators with Cropper, Less than 448 and 448 and Up (Vol. X), 1936 (Box 57)
    - One-Fourth Share Tenants (Vol. XI), 1936 (Box 56)
    - Part-Owners, One-half Share Tenants, 25% or More Receipts from Non-Farm Operations, and Discards (Vol XII), 1936 (Box 56)
  - Subseries X. Russell County, 1935
    - Index and Instructions (Vol. I), 1935 (Box 58)
    - Crops and Beef Farms (Vol. II), 1935 (Box 58)
    - Crops and Non-Beef Farms (Vol. III), 1935 (Box 59)
    - Livestock (Vol. IV), 1935 (Box 60)
    - Seeds, Manure, Fertilizer, and Lime (Vol. V), 1935 (Box 61)
    - Expense (Vol. VI), 1935 (Box 62)
    - Machinery and Equipment, Auto, Truck, and Tractor (Vol. VII), 1935 (Box 63)
    - Products and Services Used by Household, Livestock Products, and Miscellaneous Receipts (Vol. VIII), 1935 (Box 64)
    - Capital, Repairs, and Summary (Vol. IX), 1935 (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous (Vol. X), 1935 (Box 66)
    - Inventory (Vol. XI), 1935 (Box 66)
    - Feed, Fattening and Growing Herd (Vol. XII), 1935 (Box 67)
    - Feeds, Breeding, and Herd (Vol. XIII), 1935 (Box 68)
    - Pasture (Vol. XIV), 1935 (Box 69)
    - Labor (Vol. XV), 1935 (Box 70)
    - Cost Summary and Factors (Vol. XVI), 1935 (Box 71)
    - Miscellaneous and Beef Cattle (Vol. XVII), 1935 (Box 72)
    - Farm Management and Tables Not Used and Part Used (Vol. VXIII-XX), 1935 (Box 73, Box 74, Box 75)
    - Cost of Beef Production and Tables Used (Vol. XXI), 1935 (Box 76)
    - Cost of Beef Production and Tables Not Used (Vol. XXII-XXV), 1935 (Box 72, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79)
    - Beef Records (Vol. XXVI-XXVII), 1935 (Box 80)
    - Non-Beef Records (Vol. XXVIII-XXX), 1935 (Box 81)
  - Subseries XI. Truck Survey, 1938
    - Tabulations (Vol. II), 1938 (Box 82)
    - Labor Income (Vol. III), 1938 (Box 82)
  - Subseries XII. Poultry Survey, 1931-1932
    - Office Sheets 1932 Numbers (Vol. I-II), 1931-1932 (Box 83)
    - Farm Management Tabulations for Poultry Farms (Vol. III), 1931 (Box 84)
    - Inventory of Poultry for Farms Surveyed (Vol. IV), 1931-1932 (Box 85)
    - Tabulations for Poultry Cost (Vol. V-VI), 1931 (Box 86)
    - Tabulations for Poultry Cost (VIII), 1932 (Box 87)
    - Farm Management Tabulations for Poultry Farms (Vol. VII), 1932 (Box 88)
    - Tabulations for Poultry Cost (Vol. IX), 1932 (Box 89)
- Series II. Files, 1903-1947
  - Weather, 1903 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Weather, 1904 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Weather, 1905 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Weather Reports from, 1905 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Weather, 1906 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Weather, 1908-1909 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Weather, 1910 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Weather, 1911 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Weather, 1912 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Weather Reports, 1912 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Weather, 1913 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Weather, 1914 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Weather, 1915 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Weather, 1916-1917 (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Weather, 1917-1918 (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Weather, 1918-1919 (Box 90, Folder 16)
  - Weather, 1919-1920 (Box 90, Folder 17)
  - Weather Record, 1919 (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Weather, 1921 (Box 90, Folder 19)
  - Weather, 1922-1923 (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - Weather, 1923 (Box 90, Folder 21)
  - Weather, 1924 (Box 90, Folder 22)
  - Weather, 1925 (Box 90, Folder 23)
  - Weather, 1926 (Box 90, Folder 24)
  - Weather, 1927 (Box 90, Folder 25)
  - Weather, 1928 (Box 90, Folder 26)
  - Weather, 1929 (Box 90, Folder 27)
  - Weather, 1930 (Box 90, Folder 28)
  - Weather, 1931 (Box 90, Folder 29)
  - Weather, 1932 (Box 90, Folder 30)
  - Weather, 1933 (Box 90, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 32)
  - Weather, 1911-1912 (Box 90, Folder 33)
  - Crown Gall, Willey work, in part, for M.S. degree, 1906 (Box 90, Folder 34)
  - Wheat Varieties, 1906-1928 (Box 90, Folder 35)
  - Corn, 1907 (Box 90, Folder 36)
  - Corn, 1907-1911 (Box 90, Folder 37)
  - Corn, Continuous Exper., 1915-1921 (Box 90, Folder 38)
  - Stauton Notes, Corn, 1916 (Box 90, Folder 39)
  - Corn, 1917-1919 (Box 90, Folder 40)
  - Hybridization, Effect Of, On Maturity, 1917 (Box 90, Folder 41)
  - Corn, Individual Ear Study (Box 90, Folder 42)
  - Corn, Continuous Exp., 1922-1923 (Box 90, Folder 43)
  - Corn Exper. (Box 90, Folder 44)
  - Corn, Growth and Maturity Of, 1923-1931 (Box 90, Folder 45)
  - Fixation Yields, 1907-1913 (Box 90, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous extra copies, 1907-1916 (Box 90, Folder 47)
  - Acclimatization Exper., 1908-1909 (Box 90, Folder 48)
  - Acclimatization Exper., 1909-1910 (Box 90, Folder 49)
  - Acclimatization Project, 1910 (Box 90, Folder 50)
  - Appomattox, 1908-1919 (Box 90, Folder 51)
  - Appomattox (Box 90, Folder 52-53)
  - Appomattox, 1913-1914 (Box 90, Folder 54)
  - Bowling Green (tobacco, corn, hay), 1908-1913 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Bowling Green (wheat, corn, hay), 1908-1913 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Bowling Green notes prior to, 1920 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Fertilizers, Rotation Exper., 1908-1926 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Fertilizers, Rotation Exper. with, 1909-1923 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Rotation Exper., 1911-1918 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Rotation Exp., Two-year, 1913-1918 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Rotation Exp., Three-year, 1914-1918 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Rotation Exp., Five-year, 1916-1918 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Grazing Exper., 1908 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Grazing Exper., 1909-1912 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Grazing Exper. (weight of calves), 1914 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Grazing Exper. (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Louisa Station (tobacco and corn), 1908-1914 (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Grass, Analysis Of, From Sheep Plats, 1909 (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - Feeding Experiment, 1910-1925 (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - Swine and Forage Crop Invest., 1910 (Box 91, Folder 17)
  - Feeding, Short, Exp., 1920 (Box 91, Folder 18)
  - Feeding Standards-Published Data (Mr. Holdaway), 1920 (Box 91, Folder 19)
  - Feeding, 1913 (Box 91, Folder 20)
  - Feeding Experiment, 1913-1914 (Box 91, Folder 21)
  - Feeding, 1915-1916 (Box 91, Folder 22)
  - Experiment data, ca. 1913-1919 (Box 91, Folder 23-27)
  - Silage work, book 2, 1917-1918 (Box 91, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous [notebooks] (Box 91, Folder 29)
  - Notebooks, 1915-1923 (Box 92, Folder 1-11)
  - Feeding Experiment (Dr. Brainerd's notes), 1912 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - Feeding Project - miscellaneous (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - Feeding Exper., 1912 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - Feeding Project, 1913 (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - Feeding Project, 1914-1915 (Box 92, Folder 16-17)
  - Feeding Project, 1916 (Box 92, Folder 18-19)
  - Feeding, Long, Exper., 1918 (Box 92, Folder 20)
  - Feeding, Long, Exper. (new data), 1923 (Box 92, Folder 21)
  - Feeding, Long, Exper. (soy bean meal), 1923 (Box 92, Folder 22)
  - Feeding, Long, New, Exper., 1924 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Feeding, Long, New, Exper., 1925 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Feeding, Long, New, Exper., 1925-1926 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Feeding Project, Dairy Cows (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Feeding Stuffs, Commercial, Based on high energy (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Calf Feeding Exp., First, 1918 March 25 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Calf Feeding Exp. (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Calf Feeding Trial, Second, 1919 June 1 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Bui. Tables St. Exp. (Cow feeding, 5-yr. Exp.) (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Feeding, Long, New, Exper., 1925 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 93, Folder 11-14)
  - Feeding, Short, Project, 1916 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Feeding, Short, Project, Book #2, 1916 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Feeding Project, Short, Condition of Cows on, 1916 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Feeding, Long, Exper., 1917 (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Feeding Project, 1918 (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - Feeding Project, 1919 (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - Ensilage Experiment, 1916-1919 (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - Ensilage Experiment Project, 1915-1918 (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - Ensilage Exper., 1919 (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - Beef Cattle Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Grass Plat Exper., 1910 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Crozet (Role of fertilizers and moisture in tree growth and fruit bud formation), 1911-1913 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Crozet (Apple trees), 1913 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Crozet (Exper. orchard), 1914 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Crozet Experimental Orchard, 1913 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Crozet Experimental Orchard - Records, 1914 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Crozet Experimental Orchard, 1915 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Crozet Harvest Record, 1915 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Crozet - Peach, 1916 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Crozet Orchards - Exper. notes and record, 1915 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 94, Folder 12-17)
  - Varieties, Behavior of, in VA, 1911 (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Cow Peas, Variety Test, 1912-1914 (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - Cow Pea Varieties Project, 1916-1918 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Horticulture - Penn Yorks, 1912-1930 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Horticulture - Penn Yorks, 1924-1930 (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - Legume Experiment - History, 1912-1913 (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Experiments, 1912 (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - Phosphate and Lime Exp. Notes, 1912-1918 (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - Phosphate and Lime Exper., 1914 (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - Phosphate Lime Exper. Results on Corn, 1912-1918 (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - Plant Food in Soil, 1912 (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - Blacksburg - Peach and Apple Orchards, 1914 (Box 94, Folder 30)
  - Blacksburg, 1915 (Box 94, Folder 31)
  - Blacksburg Notes on Exp. Orchards, 1915 (Box 94, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 94, Folder 33-36)
  - Blacksburg - Peach Harvest Record, 1916 (Box 94, Folder 37)
  - Blacksburg - Cover Crop, 1916 (Box 94, Folder 38)
  - Blacksburg - Apple, 1916 (Box 94, Folder 39)
  - Soils, Analysis of, From Plats, 1912 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Fruit Bud Formation, 1913 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Fruit Bud Formation - Effect of Environment on, 1913 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Fruit Bud - Pruning Experiments, 1914 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Fruit Bud Formation, 1914-1915 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Green Manure Experiment, 1913 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - W.H. Burruss Ice Cream Project (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Ice Cream Making, 1916 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Protein, 1913-1916 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Pruning - Effect on Fruit Buds, 1913 (Box 95, Folder 10-11)
  - Pruning (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Pruning Exper. (King of Pippins in Full Dwarf Apple Orchard), 1915 (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Pruning, 1916 (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Soils, Virginia, 1913-1916 (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - Steer Grazing Project, 1913-1917 (Box 95, Folder 16)
  - Sudan Grass Exper., 1913 (Box 95, Folder 17)
  - Martinsville Substation, Notes on, 1913-1920 (Box 95, Folder 18)
  - Tomato Breeding, Blight-Resistant, 1913-1915 (Box 95, Folder 19)
  - Apple Trees - Exper. Plat - Planted in, 1914 (Box 95, Folder 20)
  - Cultivation Experiment Project, 1914 (Box 95, Folder 21)
  - Cyanamide for Woolly Aphis Apple Trees, 1914 (Box 95, Folder 22)
  - Macrosiphum pisi Kaltenbach, 1914-1915 (Box 95, Folder 23)
  - Soils - Greenhouse conditions, 1913-1914 (Box 95, Folder 24)
  - Schoene, W.J., State Entomologist, 1914 (Box 95, Folder 25)
  - Schoene, W.J., State Entomologist, 1914-1915 (Box 95, Folder 26)
  - Schoene, W.J., State Entomologist, 1916 (Box 95, Folder 27)
  - Schoene, W.J., State Entomologist, 1917 (Box 95, Folder 28)
  - Schoene, W.J., State Entomologist, 1918 (Box 95, Folder 29)
  - Wheat Varieties, 1914-1922 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Woolly Aphis & Crown Gall Orchards, 1914 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Alfalfa Experiments, 1915-1918 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Alfalfa - Methods of Treatment and Results, 1919 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Alfalfa Exp., Growing of, 1917-1919 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Apple Orchard Planted Spring, Running Experiments, 1915 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Fertilizers - Acid Phosphate, 1915 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Green Pea Aphid - Loren B. Smith, 1915 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Oats, Winter and Spring Varieties, Coop Exp.'s, 1915-1928 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Phosphate and Lime Experiment, 1915 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Phosphate and Phosphoric Acid in, 1915 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Stock, Notes made on condition of, 1915 May 7 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Weed Eradication Project-Results-Notes, 1915-1917 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Wheat Breeding, 1915 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Clipping Experiment, 1916-1924 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Legume Inoculation, Dr. Reed's bulletin, 1916 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Pasture Mixture, 1916-1920 (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Pasture Mixture, 1916-1924 (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Healing of Wounds - made by operation of ringing, 1916 (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - Sweet Clover Exp. Project, 1916 (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - Cover Crop Exper., 1917-1925 (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - Phosphate, 1917-1925 (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - Phosphate Experiment Project-Results-Notes, 1918-1920 (Box 96, Folder 23)
  - Potash Experiments Projects-Results-Notes, 1917-1919 (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - Reclamation Project Martinsville, 1917-1918 (Box 96, Folder 25)
  - Soil Mulch Project, 1917-1918 (Box 96, Folder 26)
  - Foreign Investigation Results, 1917-1926 (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - Soil Mulch Exp. Project-Results-Notes, 1917-1919 (Box 96, Folder 28)
  - Soybeans Notes, 1917-1924 (Box 96, Folder 29)
  - Soybean Notes and Results, 1926 (Box 96, Folder 30)
  - Soybean Trial Tables (Box 96, Folder 31)
  - Spinach Blight, 1917-1919 (Box 96, Folder 32)
  - Spinach Blight, W.J. Schoene (Box 96, Folder 33)
  - Spinach Blight notes, L.B. Smith, 1919 (Box 96, Folder 34)
  - Corn Stalk Borer Notes, 1918-1919 (Box 96, Folder 35)
  - Limestone, Ground, Exp. Project, 1918-1927 (Box 96, Folder 36)
  - Box content list, partial (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Holland Substation prior to, 1920 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Quarterly Bulletin of the Virginia State Crop Pest Commission, v. 1, no. 2 - v. 7, no. 3, 1919 July - 1925 Oct.